<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Martinez</title>
    <description>Alex Martinez is a Washington, D.C. based web designer who plays with code and currently works at iStrategyLabs. Likes include French Bulldogs, good burritos, and good company.&lt;br&gt;This site is a work in progress and is being built with Jekyll and hosted on Github.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 12:41:04 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 12:41:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alex Martinez – Meet Edgar</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;resume-container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/a/alxmrtnz.com/file/d/0BxO3zT6SvWvFMkQyeDdSUXRSTDA/preview&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/resume-postlight/index.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/resume-postlight/index.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Optimizing Onboarding for Benchmarcs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Through &lt;a href=&quot;http://metto.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Metto&lt;/a&gt; , I helped design and build a web application called &lt;a href=&quot;http://benchmarcs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Benchmarcs&lt;/a&gt; that allows funeral homes to monitor trends in business for both their own individual homes and their competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, funeral homes tracked “calls,” or deaths, by skimming through obituaries in local newspapers and obituary websites. Because the calls listed in these sources also indicated which funeral home would be performing the funeral, each home could track how much business each competitor was receiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Benchmarcs, we helped automate this process by using web spiders to crawl online data and assess when and where calls happen. This helps homes save time and money and provides a central hub of important competitive data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-new-users-with-actionable-content&quot;&gt;Setting Up New Users with Actionable Content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest advantages in moving toward an automated system like Benchmarcs is that it gives funeral homes the ability to track their competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding competitors allows users to see how many calls a competing home received over the last week, month, year, etc and also see trends in calls over that period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to educate new users about the ability to track competitors and to help populate their accounts with competitor data, &lt;em&gt;we decided to integrate the ability to add competitors into the onboarding process&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image__container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-onboarding-v3.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-onboarding-v3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Benchmarcs Onboarding User Flow&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;We created user-flow diagrams to outline functionality in the initial onboarding and setup, including the ability to add competitor funeral homes (Getting Started Step 3)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating-funeral-home-needs&quot;&gt;Evaluating Funeral Home Needs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversations with our product owners and several potential users led us to focus on the addition of competitors on a local, rather than regional or national level. We learned that even when a competitor has multiple locations across a state or region, funeral homes tend to focus on the competing branch closest to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To allow users to add competing funeral homes, we started by approximating the user’s location to show a suggested set of homes in their area. The page displayed the user’s closest zip code and provided a radius selector to filter results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image__container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-add-competitors-v1.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-add-competitors-v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Benchmarcs Add a Competitor Wireframe and design V1&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;
		We gathered user feedback on the initial &quot;add a competitor&quot; feature from several pilot program users.
	&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-the-initial-design&quot;&gt;Improving the Initial Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some aspects of the initial functionality fit the bill, the nuances of the design did not. New users would choose several homes from the pre-populated list before becoming frustrated when they couldn’t find the home they were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was unclear to users that the list of homes was a smaller list of suggestions rather than a complete list of all competitors. In the end, this solution made the tool less useful to users and converted them with less competitors than than they really wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several of usability sessions, our team decided to improve the design of this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iterating-to-improve-usability&quot;&gt;Iterating to Improve Usability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To improve usability, we made a couple of changes to both the visual design and functionality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We did away with ZIP and radius&lt;/strong&gt; – user testing had shown that these fields were not being used and that users instead focused on the search input&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We made the search bar more prominent&lt;/strong&gt; in order to guide the user to take action&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We added the title “Suggested Competitors” to the preloaded competitors list&lt;/strong&gt; to communicate to users that this initial list wasn’t exhausted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We added functionality to deliver more and more relevant results on each selection.&lt;/strong&gt; Now, each time the user picks a competitor, we hit the Benchmarcs API, search for homes near the selected competitor and add them to the list of suggestions. Then, we  re-sort the list based on how many times a competitor is suggested in relation to the competitors selected by the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image__container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-interaction.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-interaction.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Adding a Competitor - Animated GIF&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;
		Version two of the &quot;add a competitor&quot; feature led to an overall increase in competitors added by users when setting up their accounts.
	&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While seemingly small, the updated design makes the tool more useful to user and has increased the number of homes a new user would add during setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only could users find the homes they were looking for, but the updated functionality helped give them better suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When it comes to the design of a feature, the smallest details can create a big impact.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if it’s simply modifying a label or moving an input, a change in design can drastically affect the end user’s experience with your product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User test throughout the design and development process&lt;/strong&gt; in order to uncover areas for improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always be iterating.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s easy to become complacent, but the best solutions come through thoughtful refinements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 15:46:27 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/thoughts/optimizing-onboarding-for-benchmarcs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thoughts/optimizing-onboarding-for-benchmarcs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Improving and Driving Discovery on Service Year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/work/service-year&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Service Year&lt;/a&gt; is the nation’s largest marketplace for year-long, full-time, paid service opportunities. It allows young Americans to discover full-time, paid, year-long service opportunities with organizations from across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High school students that want to contribute to something meaningful during a gap year before college, college graduates trying to find a higher calling, or any young American between the ages of 18-24 can use the platform to connect with impactful organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platform’s focus on connection between organizations and service corps members depends upon the ability for users to find listings and organizations that are tailored to their interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after the first iteration of the discovery flow, we found that building the bridge for users was not happening. Users were having difficulty understanding what a “service year” was and how to find positions and get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discovering the right position and getting involved with the right organization required a simpler path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding a listing for a service position should be a simple experience that’s tailored to a user’s interests. However, after conducting in-person and online usability tests with real users, it was clear that the path to discovery was foggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating the MVP for the platform (which including the public facing marketing pages and a log in system for corps members and organizations), our team was tasked with building out the ability to search listings, positions, organizations, and users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a flexible system for displaying different content types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through usability sessions, we identified three key painpoints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Site navigation created an unclear path&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The homepage did not clearly explain the process of getting involved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Narrowing down search results was difficult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-team-effort&quot;&gt;A Team Effort&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a product being designed and built by my company, &lt;a href=&quot;https://isl.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;ISL&lt;/a&gt;, but owned by a client, &lt;a href=&quot;https://isl.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;The Service Year Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, working on this challenge involved a variety of team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;img src=&quot;https://placekitten.com/1400/600&quot; /&gt;
    	&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;A look at the homepage used in testing.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-flows&quot;&gt;User Flows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These fictional personas allowed us to create user flows that aided in the identification of discrete goals and actions for each type of user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-user-flow-david.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;site-structure&quot;&gt;Site Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After analyzing user flows and also interviewing stakeholders, we reorganized content into three main buckets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Family Resources (Good digital Parenting)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policy and Research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concentrating of FOSI’s pre-existing content into three main buckets simplified the process of finding content for the end user. Not only that, but the structure allowed us to make content a priority something something here…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[sitemap here]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prototyping&quot;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the functionality we wanted to include in the site, such as a sticky navigation and fixed filters, are often difficult to describe to clients using static wireframes. To better communicate the small details that would improve the new FOSI experience, our team created a set of animated wireframes in addition to our standard wireframe set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/155266319?autoplay=1&amp;amp;loop=1&amp;amp;loop=1&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-wireframes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;typography&quot;&gt;Typography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to be inviting to parents, yet authoritative and reliable to professionals, I chose typefaces that mixed organic sans-serif headings with more traditional serifed text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-type-example.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aaux-next&quot;&gt;Aaux Next&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaux Next is an approachabe sans-serif that was chosen for headings due to its mix of solid structure and rounded, more quirky, characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;minion-pro&quot;&gt;Minion Pro&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minion Pro exhibits functional qualities that makes text highly readable. I chose it to give formality and legibility to the site’s main content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;colors&quot;&gt;Colors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With content being broken up into several main sections, I defined colors that would be related to each type of content (green for Good Digital Parenting, red for Policy &amp;amp; Research, etc). By tying specific colors to content, we were able to visually separate internal platforms each internal platform and give the user clear context to their location on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fin-tip&quot;&gt;	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
	A Flexible, Responsive Publishing Platform
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, the new FOSI.org is a multi-faceted publishing platform. From online-safety print outs to the latest research on internet privacy, FOSI works to publish educational content that helps families (and the industry at large) learn and grow in the new digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By creating flexible layouts, a new design system, and an integration with Wagtail, a Django-based CMS, we were able to provide FOSI with a rethought and redesigned responsive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/benchmarcs/app-screenshots/benchmarcs-marketing-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Benchmarcs Marketing Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half &quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/benchmarcs/app-screenshots/benchmarcs-screenshot-call-volume.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Benchmarcs app – Call Volume Chart&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half end&quot;&gt;
		 &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/benchmarcs/app-screenshots/benchmarcs-screenshot-market-share.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Benchmarcs app – Market Share Graph&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/zapier2/index.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/zapier2/index.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Question Three</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;prompt&quot;&gt;Prompt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell me about a time you worked on a project designed to increase conversion rates or usage of a specific feature. What was the process, who did you collaborate with, and what was the outcome? Make sure to include sketches, wireframes, mockups, screenshots, and narrative to effectively describe your design process towards designing and building this feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through &lt;a href=&quot;http://metto.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Metto&lt;/a&gt; , I helped design and build a web application called Benchmarcs that allows funeral homes to monitor trends in business for both their own individual homes and their competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, funeral homes tracked “calls,” or deaths, by skimming through obituaries in local newspapers and obituary websites. Because the calls listed in these sources also indicated which funeral home would be performing the funeral, each home could track how much business each competitor was receiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Benchmarcs, we helped automate this process by using web spiders to crawl online data and assess when and where calls happen. This helps homes save time and money and provides a central hub of important competitive data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tracking-the-competition&quot;&gt;Tracking the Competition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest advantages in moving toward an automated system like Benchmarcs is that it gives funeral homes the ability to track their competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding competitors allows users to see how many calls a competing home received over the last week, month, year, etc and also see trends in calls over that period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to educate new users about the ability to track competitors and to help populate their accounts with competitor data, we decided to integrate the ability to add competitors into the onboarding process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image__container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-onboarding-v3.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-onboarding-v3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Benchmarcs Onboarding User Flow&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;We created user-flow diagrams to outline functionality in the initial onboarding and setup, including the ability to add competitor funeral homes (Getting Started Step 3)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversations with our product owners and several potential users led us to focus on the addition of competitors on a local, rather than regional or national level. We learned that even when the competition has multiple locations across a state or region, homes tend to focus on the competing branch closest to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In allow users to add competing funeral homes, we started by approximating the user’s location in order to show an suggested set of homes in their area. The page displayed the user’s closest zip code and provided a radius selector to filter results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image__container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-add-competitors-v1.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-add-competitors-v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Benchmarcs Add a Competitor Wireframe and design V1&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;
		We gathered user feedback on the initial &quot;add a competitor&quot; feature from several pilot program users.
	&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some aspects of the initial functionality fit the bill, the nuances of the design did not. New users would choose several homes from the pre-populated list before becoming frustrated when they couldn’t find the home they were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was unclear to users that the list of homes was a smaller list of suggestions rather than a complete list of all competitors. In the end, this solution made the tool less useful to users and converted them with less competitors than than they really wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several of usability sessions, our team decided to improve the design of this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To improve usability, we made a couple of changes to both the visual design and functionality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We did away with ZIP and radius&lt;/strong&gt; – user testing had shown that these fields were not being used and that users instead focused on the search input&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We made the search bar more prominent&lt;/strong&gt; in order to guide the user to take action&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We added the title “Suggested Competitors” to the preloaded competitors list&lt;/strong&gt; to communicate to users that this initial list wasn’t exhausted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We added functionality to deliver more and more relevant results on each selection.&lt;/strong&gt; Now, each time the user picks a competitor, we hit the Benchmarcs API, search for homes near the selected competitor and add them to the list of suggestions. Then, we  re-sort the list based on how many times a competitor is suggested in relation to the competitors selected by the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image__container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-interaction.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;pop-out-image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/zapier/images/benchmarcs-interaction.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Adding a Competitor - Animated GIF&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;
		Version two of the &quot;add a competitor&quot; feature led to an overall increase in competitors added by users when setting up their accounts.
	&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While seemingly small, the updated design makes the tool more useful to user and has increased the number of homes a new user would add during setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only could users find the homes they were looking for, but the updated functionality helped give them better suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-team&quot;&gt;The Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on Benchmarcs with with a small team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metto.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Metto&lt;/a&gt;, a fully remote design and development studio. The core team includes two designers (another product designer and me) and two developers who split duties on frontend and backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also helped style the front-end side of the application and worked with the application’s Backbone framework, Marionette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the team at Metto, we work closely with the application’s product owners, Tyler and Michael Anderson, the CEO and VP of Marketing and Business Development at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theoutlookgroup.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;The Outlook Group&lt;/a&gt;*, to build the standalone application that they are currently marketing to funeral homes in the midwest and across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
  *Outlook Group is one of the nation’s largest marketing firms in the pre-need funeral industry.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When it comes to the design of a feature, the smallest details can create a big impact.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if it’s simply modifying a label or moving an input, a change in design can drastically affect the end user’s experience with your product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User test throughout the design and development process&lt;/strong&gt; in order to uncover areas for improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always be iterating.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s easy to become complacent, but the best solutions come through thoughtful refinements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/zapier/index.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/zapier/index.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Service Year</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid--featured-image grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/181189760?color=00fbe6&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-overview&quot;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Service Year Alliance teamed up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://isl.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;ISL&lt;/a&gt; to design and develop a digital platform for young Americans to connect and serve with the nation’s best nonprofits. Service Year aims to make a year of service a common expectation and opportunity for every young American.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ongoing and ever-evolving project, the site brings the nation’s best service opportunities into one place, allowing both organizations and service corps members to more easily connect with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-role&quot;&gt;My Role&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I served as a lead visual and user experience designer on Service Year. While working with a team of designers, developers, and project managers within ISL, we also worked closely with our client, the Service Year Alliance to bring their vision to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the project, I worked on anything from initial user research to the creation of user flows, wireframes, and interactive prototypes to the final visual and interaction design of both the marketing site and web application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-the-service-year-ecosystem&quot;&gt;Creating the Service Year Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Service Year is built on the idea of connecting organizations with American youth, we needed to create a platform that catered to a variety of users and content types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re the administrator that manages your organization’s profile and prescense on Service Year, someone recruiting service members for an organization, or an individual looking for a service opportunity, Service Year needs to connect you to where you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;information-architecture&quot;&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning in the kickoff meeting with our client, we began to assess everything that would make up the Service Year Exchange platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial sitemaps helped our team lay out initial screens for everything from the marketing pages to the various interactions users would take when listing and discovering service opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/sy-site-map-august-2015.png&quot; alt=&quot;Service Year Sitemap (August 2015)&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;Initial sitemaps can give an idea of the number of screens/interactions needed for a project of this scale.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-flows&quot;&gt;User Flows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then began creating user flows for the paths each user type would take when being brought onto the system, browsing opportunities, or recruiting corps members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/org-enroll-corps-member-flow-5-11-16.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Userflow&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;User flows allowed our team to define the paths users would take to accomplish tasks.&lt;br /&gt;This user flow shows a corps member expressing interest in a position and an organization&#39;s path to taking action on that interest.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While user flows were an essential part to getting the project started, it wasn’t always such a linear process. Our team worked within an agile process, using two-week sprints to accomplish tasks on a story-by-story basis. We iterated on different parts of the UX and design process depending on the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wireframes--prototypes&quot;&gt;Wireframes &amp;amp; Prototypes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each new page or interaction being added to the system, our team would create sets of wireframes in Sketch, Balsamiq, Omnigraffle, or even just pen-and-paper sketchs. Often, we linked these wireframes together in &lt;a href=&quot;http://invisionapp.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; in order to get a sense of how the screens would connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/sy-invision-screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Service Year Invision Prototype Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;
			Prototypes allowed us to think through flows for different user interactions. Here is an early prototype of onboarding new corps members to Service Year. 
			&lt;br /&gt;
			(&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/invision/sy-cm-onboarding-wireframe-prototype/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;View Prototype in New Window&lt;/a&gt;)	
		&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototyping allowed us to see when certain interactions felt great (or just awkward). Not only that, but it also allowed us to share in-progress work with our client and receive quick feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the scale of Service Year, our team worked around the idea of component-based design. Each part of a page not only needed consideration in terms of responsive design, but also necessitated the creation of assets for multiple states. Each component then had to work alongside other components in the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of component-based design helped us to define atoms and molecules that could then be used to build organisms, templates, and finally, pages (&lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/atomic-web-design/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;See Brad Frost’s Atomic Design&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt &quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/sy-narrative-components.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Service Year Component Screenshot - Serving Status Cards&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;
	    	A look at the different states for the serving status block within a Corps Member&#39;s public profile.
	    &lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-living-design-system&quot;&gt;A Living Design System&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While web style guides and frameworks have been around for several years, the explosion of large-scale web applications brings an extra focus on creating design systems. Style guides like Salesforce’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lightningdesignsystem.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Lightning Design System&lt;/a&gt; or Dropbox’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://dropbox.github.io/scooter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Scooter&lt;/a&gt; have set a standard for the design community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our design and development teams collaborated to create our own living style guide for the Service Year platform. The style guide is ever-evolving and allows for better design/dev collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/sy-style-guide.png&quot; alt=&quot;Service Year Style Guide Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;
			The Service Year Style Guide helps designers and developers to collaborate when designing, building, and iterating on components. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://serviceyear.org/styleguide/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;View Style Guide&lt;/a&gt;)
		&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-in-agile&quot;&gt;Working in Agile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Service Year is the largest web application that has ever come through ISL. With such new territory came the need to figure out new and effective processes for managing, designing, and developing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the onset, our team implemented an &lt;a href=&quot;http://agilemanifesto.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;agile workflow&lt;/a&gt; in order to quickly design, build, and ship iterations of the Service Year platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/sy-sprint-tracker-and-waffle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Sprint Tracker and Waffle Board&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;
			A backlog of user stories were defined in collaboration with the client and saved in a Google Spreadsheet. During each sprint cycle, we then used Github and Waffle to monitor progress on each task.
		&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborating with the client, our workflow began with the creation of user stories that defined functionality for the platform. Both the design and development teams would take these user stories from a Google Spreadseet backlog and work on them in 2 to 3 week sprint cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only were we iterating on Service Year as a platform, but we were constantly learning what worked best within our own workflow and modifying our processes accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fin-tip&quot;&gt;		
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
	Conclusion &amp;amp; Lessons Learned
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on a product that makes such a positive impact is a very rewarding experience. Service Year is an ever-evolving platform and the largest web application that I’ve been involved in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of things stuck out to me during my work on Service Year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-large-scale-applications&quot;&gt;Building Large Scale Applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design systems for large scale applications take a lot more work than you may think. I learned through Service Year how important collaboration between design, development, and project managers is key to a successful project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning-to-fail-and-improve&quot;&gt;Learning to Fail and Improve&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re never going to get a design 100% right the first time and that’s ok. The iterative process of short design and development sprints allow room for testing new ideas, learning their shortcomings through user-testing, and then improving on the next go-round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-design-processes&quot;&gt;New Design Processes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Service Year helped me learn how to work within a new type of workflow. Before this project, I had most often been involved in more traditional waterfall workflows. With Service Year, I learned more about the cyclical and collaborative nature of an agile sprint process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/sy-homepage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Service Year Home Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow &quot;&gt;
		 &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/sy-comps-profile-tablet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Service Year Corps Member Profile (Tablet)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow end&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/serviceyear/sy-comps-sign-in.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Service Year Sign In Pages (Desktop)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text--centered&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://serviceyear.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;ServiceYear.org&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 15:46:27 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/work/service-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/service-year.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alex Martinez – Resume</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;resume-container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/a/alxmrtnz.com/file/d/0BxO3zT6SvWvFUG9VZ3NLWmt3M0k/preview&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/resume/index.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/resume/index.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alex Martinez – Meet Edgar</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;resume-container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/a/alxmrtnz.com/file/d/0BxO3zT6SvWvFa1lzRGMyM0NEcms/preview&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/meetedgar-resume/index.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/meetedgar-resume/index.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outlook Relationship Management System</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid--featured-image grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/featured-image-orms.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theoutlookgroup.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;The Outlook Group&lt;/a&gt; is one of the nation’s largest marketing firms in the pre-need* funeral industry and has a national team of sales representatives who work with individual funeral homes to maintain and develop their own customer bases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked with the group and a small team to create the Outlook Relationship Management System (ORMS), a web application that improves the workflow of The Outlook Group’s sales representatives and client funeral homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I focused on establishing the overall visual language and user experience of the platform and also worked closely with project developers throughout implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
  * pre-need services include things such as pre-need life insurance policies that cover the cost of predetermined expense of a funeral, cremation, or burial.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunity-management&quot;&gt;Opportunity Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To allow Outlook Group sales representatives to record and monitor potential customers, we designed a robust opportunities management page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning with simple sketches, we were able to validate functionality with Outlook Group stakeholders before moving into visual design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-wireframe-sketches__opportunities.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Wireframe Sketch - Opportunities Table&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;One of our first wireframe iterations for managing customer prospects, leads, and accounts (credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zachkuzmic.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zach Kuzmic&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through iteration, we designed and implemented essential functionality for filtering, searching, and sorting opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-screenshot__opportunities@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Opportunities Table&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;Several iterations of wireframes and visual design led to a robust page for managing sales opportunities.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;task-management-and-collaboration&quot;&gt;Task Management and Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We paid special attention to how Outlook Group sales reps collaborate around individual opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can add and categorize notes in a timeline format for easy future reference, create custom tasks, and schedule appointments that tie into the app’s calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this functionality is available between multiple system users, allowing sales reps to collaboratively record and monitor information on each opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-screenshot__opportunity-detail@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Opportunity Detail Page&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;Users can collaborate on individual opportunities through the use of notes, tasks, and appointments.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;system-vs-custom-tagging&quot;&gt;System vs Custom Tagging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another piece of functionality we were added to ORMS was tagging. ORMS allows users to create custom tags for each opportunity in addition to the base set of tags that Outlook Group admins create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Outlook Tags,” not only help guide their sales reps in the creation of their own custom tags, but also provides valuable usage data to Outlook Group admins for future iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-detail__tags.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Calendar&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calendar-integration&quot;&gt;Calendar Integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An in-app calendar that can integrate with any major calendar provider proved an important part of the ORMS system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both sales reps and Outlook Group admins needed the ability to track appointments with potential opportunities and current customers. Additionally, admins are able to access employee calendars to help coordinate business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calendar we designed and implemented integrates with Google and allows for everyone within the Outlook Group to stay on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-screenshot__calendar@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Calendar&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-responsive-visual-system&quot;&gt;A Responsive, Visual System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning of the project, we focused on creating a responsive web application experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I began the visual design process, I worked on identifying some base styles and flexible components that could be reused across the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-detail__responsive@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Various Responsive Mobile Screens&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption text--centered&quot;&gt;I worked on creating a responsive card system that could accomodate graphs, tables, calendars, and more.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fin-tip&quot;&gt;	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
	Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ORMS has become a robust internal tool for a national workforce. With a small team and close collaboration with our client, we were able to deliver a fully-responsive CRM that suits the Outlook Group’s specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 15:46:27 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/work/orms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/orms.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PAW (Puppies at Work)</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid--featured-image grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/160030363?color=00fbe6&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At ISL, we’re constantly exploring ways to take advantage of new technologies. In honor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalpuppyday.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;National Puppy Day&lt;/a&gt;, we created PAW, or “Puppies at Work,” a Slack-integrated tracking system to keep track of dogs in the workspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project comprised of connecting the physical and digital worlds through a bluetooth tracking system that linked to a web application for viewing the location of dogs in the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an in-depth look at how it works, &lt;a href=&quot;https://isl.co/2016/03/a-slack-based-internet-of-things-iot-tracking-system-for-your-dog-hello-paw/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;read more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-overview&quot;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the latest ISL experiment, PAW was comprised of a small internal team that brought the product to life in a few short weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I served as front-end developer for the public facing marketing page and also helped in the styling of the internal dashboard application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had the opportunity to explore animating SVGs through CSS (thanks to the illustrative work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/sarahsugarman&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Sarah Sugarman&lt;/a&gt;) and worked with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/krawchyk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Andrew Krawchyk&lt;/a&gt;, the project’s development lead, to implement some of the front-end application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/paw/paw-marketing-page-screenshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	    
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow end&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/paw/paw-dashboard-screenshots.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;animating-svgs&quot;&gt;Animating SVGs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I began development, I wanted to work on animating the various components of the marketing page’s hero illustration in order to create a playful and interesting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by exporting three parts of the scene for animation: a coffee mug, the computer screen, and, of course, Watson – our PAW mascot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After combing through the SVG code, I targeted specific shapes for animation and got them moving through the use of CSS animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p data-height=&quot;750&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;light&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;LGBbOv&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;alxmrtnz&quot; data-embed-version=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/alxmrtnz/pen/LGBbOv/&quot;&gt;Workspace Animation&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Martinez (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/alxmrtnz&quot;&gt;@alxmrtnz&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

		&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;Animating SVGs through CSS gave the landing page illustration a life of its own.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explored animation loops through relatively simple CSS properties. Elements like the coffee’s steam were particularly interesting because of the need for offset timing to achieve an effect of easing in and out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsive-development&quot;&gt;Responsive Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to working on SVG animations, my other task at hand was to develop the public-facing marketing page and also to lend support for the internal application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/paw/paw-responsive-screenshots.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/paw/paw-homepage-screenshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PAW is currently available to ISL employees only. To learn more about PAW, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://isl.co/2016/03/a-slack-based-internet-of-things-iot-tracking-system-for-your-dog-hello-paw/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://paw.isl.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;visit the site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 15:46:27 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/work/paw.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/paw.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Washington Leadership Academy</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid--featured-image grid--no-bg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full &quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img class=&quot;item-img--full&quot; src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/featured-image-wla.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-overview&quot;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Washington Leadership Academy is a public charter school working to change the way we think about high school education. With a mission to provide sutdents in the District of Columbia with the knowledge, skills and habits required for success in college and lives of public leadership, WLA came to our team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isl.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;ISL&lt;/a&gt; for a branding and website overhaul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project presented our team with a unique opportunity to create a site from the ground up on Squarespace, design and build a client project in the open, give back to our local community, and help lead the way for a new kind high school education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-a-modular-design-system&quot;&gt;Creating a Modular Design System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to create a custom Squarespace site that would be easily customizeable and maintainable in the future, our team crafted a set of reusable and modular components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wireframing-and-prototyping&quot;&gt;Wireframing and Prototyping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started the project with the goal of creating 4 to 5 unique template pages. In order to rapidly wireframe and prototype (due to the tight project timeline), I ended up created wireframes using a set of several repeated components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-wireframe-homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframe of WLA&#39;s Home Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half end&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-wireframe-about.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframe of WLA&#39;s About Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repeated components comprising our initial wireframes evolved through collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://heyitsolivia.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Olivia Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, our lead developer on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her exploration of Squarespace as a development platform made it clear that we could use Squarespace as a CMS to implement the site on a component by component basis and provide WLA with a more flexible and customizable end experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several internal wireframing workshops to validate the value of each component, I created several &lt;a href=&quot;https://invisionapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; prototypes to share with the client and receive any necessary feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/team-wireframe-workshop1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ISL team wireframing workshop&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;We held several internal wireframing workshops to identify reusable components and used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; to create interactive prototypes.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I worked through the IA/UX of the project, my colleague &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dribbble.com/thepaleshadow/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;James Bonilla&lt;/a&gt; simultaneously worked with WLA to create a brand for their online and offline presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to incorporating the James’s branding into the site, it was at this time that I focused on responsive states of each individual component. I worked closely with our front-end developer to evaluate the design solution for each component and used Github to track our progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/responsive-screenshots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Responsive Blocks&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was important that the site reflect the new brand and also expand upon it. Using the new brand’s cool colors and elegant sans-serif and serif typefaces created a feeling of modern prestige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other elements, such as offset image and text blocks and use of diagonal lines, make the site and the WLA brand feel more dynamic and forward-thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designing--developing-in-the-open&quot;&gt;Designing &amp;amp; Developing in the Open&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With approval from the WLA team, we were able to open source both the design and development of the project on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our initial goal was to use Github as an internal tool for collaboration but it also ended up allowing our team to document design and development decisions for future contributors to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-tools-we-used&quot;&gt;The Tools We Used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;github&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to track each individual component, from design to development, we used Github’s issues feature. Using issues allowed both design and development to add comments, screenshots, and statuses to each component as it made its way through our process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;waffle&quot;&gt;Waffle&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we integrated our Github repository with &lt;a href=&quot;http://waffle.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Waffle.io&lt;/a&gt;. Using Github issues and Waffle allowed us to create a Kanban board to track progress and collaborate on each feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/waffle-and-github.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshots of Waffle and Github&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption text--centered&quot;&gt;We held several internal wireframing workshops to identify reusable components and used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; to create interactive prototypes.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;documentation&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we didn’t love Github enough already, we even took advantage of Github’s wiki functionality to create and delivered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/washington-leadership-academy/wla/wiki/WLA-Squarespace-User-Guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;user guide&lt;/a&gt; to WLA for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This iterative, Kanban style process made it easy for our team to track design and development progress and effectively meet a tight deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fin-tip top-margin-large&quot;&gt;	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
	Takeaways
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From exploring new workflows and processes to iterating on a design at a component-by-component level to furthering my understanding of what it means to collaborate, working on the new WLA site was a very educational and fulfilling experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, we don’t have the opportunity to work on a project that will benefit so many young individuals. WLA has some exciting things in store and if you haven’t already, make sure to check out their &lt;a href=&quot;http://washingtonleadershipacademy.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-homepage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of WLA Home Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-student-life-page-mobile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of WLA Student Life Page (mobile)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow end&quot;&gt;
		 &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-about-page-tablet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of WLA About Page (tablet)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text--centered&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://washingtonleadershipacademy.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;WashingtonLeadershipAcademy.org&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 15:46:27 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/work/wla.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/wla.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
