<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Martinez</title>
    <description>Alex Martinez is a Washington, D.C. based web designer who plays with code and currently works at iStrategyLabs. Likes include French Bulldogs, good burritos, and good company.&lt;br&gt;This site is a work in progress and is being built with Jekyll and hosted on Github.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 11:18:42 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 11:18:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outlook Relationship Management System</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid--featured-image grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/featured-image-orms.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theoutlookgroup.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;The Outlook Group&lt;/a&gt; is one of the nation’s largest marketing firms in the pre-need* funeral industry and has a national team of sales representatives who work with individual funeral homes to maintain and develop their own customer bases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked with the group and a small team to create the Outlook Relationship Management System (ORMS), a web application that improves the workflow of The Outlook Group’s sales representatives and client funeral homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I focused on establishing the overall visual language and user experience of the platform and also worked closely with project developers throughout implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
  * pre-need services include things such as pre-need life insurance policies that cover the cost of predetermined expense of a funeral, cremation, or burial.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunity-management&quot;&gt;Opportunity Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To allow Outlook Group sales representatives to record and monitor potential customers, we designed a robust opportunities management page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning with simple sketches, we were able to validate functionality with Outlook Group stakeholders before moving into visual design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-wireframe-sketches__opportunities.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Wireframe Sketch - Opportunities Table&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;One of our first wireframe iterations for managing customer prospects, leads, and accounts (credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zachkuzmic.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zach Kuzmic&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through iteration, we designed and implemented essential functionality for filtering, searching, and sorting opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-screenshot__opportunities@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Opportunities Table&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;Several iterations of wireframes and visual design led to a robust page for managing sales opportunities.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;task-management-and-collaboration&quot;&gt;Task Management and Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We paid special attention to how Outlook Group sales reps collaborate around individual opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can add and categorize notes in a timeline format for easy future reference, create custom tasks, and schedule appointments that tie into the app’s calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this functionality is available between multiple system users, allowing sales reps to collaboratively record and monitor information on each opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-screenshot__opportunity-detail@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Opportunity Detail Page&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;Users can collaborate on individual opportunities through the use of notes, tasks, and appointments.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;system-vs-custom-tagging&quot;&gt;System vs Custom Tagging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another piece of functionality we were added to ORMS was tagging. ORMS allows users to create custom tags for each opportunity in addition to the base set of tags that Outlook Group admins create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Outlook Tags,” not only help guide their sales reps in the creation of their own custom tags, but also provides valuable usage data to Outlook Group admins for future iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-detail__tags.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Calendar&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calendar-integration&quot;&gt;Calendar Integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An in-app calendar that can integrate with any major calendar provider proved an important part of the ORMS system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both sales reps and Outlook Group admins needed the ability to track appointments with potential opportunities and current customers. Additionally, admins are able to access employee calendars to help coordinate business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calendar we designed and implemented integrates with Google and allows for everyone within the Outlook Group to stay on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-screenshot__calendar@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Calendar&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-responsive-visual-system&quot;&gt;A Responsive, Visual System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning of the project, we focused on creating a responsive web application experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I began the visual design process, I worked on identifying some base styles and flexible components that could be reused across the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/orms/orms-detail__responsive@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;ORMS Application Screenshot - Various Responsive Mobile Screens&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption text--centered&quot;&gt;I worked on creating a responsive card system that could accomodate graphs, tables, calendars, and more.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fin-tip&quot;&gt;	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
	Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ORMS has become a robust internal tool for a national workforce. With a small team and close collaboration with our client, we were able to deliver a fully-responsive CRM that suits the Outlook Group’s specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 14:46:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/work/orms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/orms.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Washington Leadership Academy</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid--featured-image grid--no-bg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full &quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img class=&quot;item-img--full&quot; src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/featured-image-wla.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-overview&quot;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Washington Leadership Academy is a public charter school working to change the way we think about high school education. With a mission to provide sutdents in the District of Columbia with the knowledge, skills and habits required for success in college and lives of public leadership, WLA came to our team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isl.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;ISL&lt;/a&gt; for a branding and website overhaul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project presented our team with a unique opportunity to create a site from the ground up on Squarespace, design and build a client project in the open, give back to our local community, and help lead the way for a new kind high school education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-a-modular-design-system&quot;&gt;Creating a Modular Design System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to create a custom Squarespace site that would be easily customizeable and maintainable in the future, our team crafted a set of reusable and modular components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wireframing-and-prototyping&quot;&gt;Wireframing and Prototyping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started the project with the goal of creating 4 to 5 unique template pages. In order to rapidly wireframe and prototype (due to the tight project timeline), I ended up created wireframes using a set of several repeated components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-wireframe-homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframe of WLA&#39;s Home Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half end&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-wireframe-about.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframe of WLA&#39;s About Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repeated components comprising our initial wireframes evolved through collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://heyitsolivia.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Olivia Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, our lead developer on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her exploration of Squarespace as a development platform made it clear that we could use Squarespace as a CMS to implement the site on a component by component basis and provide WLA with a more flexible and customizable end experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several internal wireframing workshops to validate the value of each component, I created several &lt;a href=&quot;https://invisionapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; prototypes to share with the client and receive any necessary feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/team-wireframe-workshop1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ISL team wireframing workshop&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;We held several internal wireframing workshops to identify reusable components and used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; to create interactive prototypes.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I worked through the IA/UX of the project, my colleague &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dribbble.com/thepaleshadow/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;James Bonilla&lt;/a&gt; simultaneously worked with WLA to create a brand for their online and offline presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to incorporating the James’s branding into the site, it was at this time that I focused on responsive states of each individual component. I worked closely with our front-end developer to evaluate the design solution for each component and used Github to track our progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/responsive-screenshots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Responsive Blocks&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was important that the site reflect the new brand and also expand upon it. Using the new brand’s cool colors and elegant sans-serif and serif typefaces created a feeling of modern prestige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other elements, such as offset image and text blocks and use of diagonal lines, make the site and the WLA brand feel more dynamic and forward-thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designing--developing-in-the-open&quot;&gt;Designing &amp;amp; Developing in the Open&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With approval from the WLA team, we were able to open source both the design and development of the project on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our initial goal was to use Github as an internal tool for collaboration but it also ended up allowing our team to document design and development decisions for future contributors to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-tools-we-used&quot;&gt;The Tools We Used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;github&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to track each individual component, from design to development, we used Github’s issues feature. Using issues allowed both design and development to add comments, screenshots, and statuses to each component as it made its way through our process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;waffle&quot;&gt;Waffle&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we integrated our Github repository with &lt;a href=&quot;http://waffle.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Waffle.io&lt;/a&gt;. Using Github issues and Waffle allowed us to create a Kanban board to track progress and collaborate on each feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/waffle-and-github.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshots of Waffle and Github&quot; /&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;img-caption text--centered&quot;&gt;We held several internal wireframing workshops to identify reusable components and used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; to create interactive prototypes.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;documentation&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we didn’t love Github enough already, we even took advantage of Github’s wiki functionality to create and delivered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/washington-leadership-academy/wla/wiki/WLA-Squarespace-User-Guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;user guide&lt;/a&gt; to WLA for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This iterative, Kanban style process made it easy for our team to track design and development progress and effectively meet a tight deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fin-tip top-margin-large&quot;&gt;	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
	Takeaways
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From exploring new workflows and processes to iterating on a design at a component-by-component level to furthering my understanding of what it means to collaborate, working on the new WLA site was a very educational and fulfilling experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, we don’t have the opportunity to work on a project that will benefit so many young individuals. WLA has some exciting things in store and if you haven’t already, make sure to check out their &lt;a href=&quot;http://washingtonleadershipacademy.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-homepage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of WLA Home Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-student-life-page-mobile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of WLA Student Life Page (mobile)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow end&quot;&gt;
		 &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/wla/wla-about-page-tablet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of WLA About Page (tablet)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text--centered&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://washingtonleadershipacademy.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;WashingtonLeadershipAcademy.org&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 14:46:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/work/wla.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/wla.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PAW (Puppies at Work)</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid--featured-image grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/160030363?color=00fbe6&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At ISL, we’re constantly exploring ways to take advantage of new technologies. In honor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalpuppyday.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;National Puppy Day&lt;/a&gt;, we created PAW, or “Puppies at Work,” a Slack-integrated tracking system to keep track of dogs in the workspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project comprised of connecting the physical and digital worlds through a bluetooth tracking system that linked to a web application for viewing the location of dogs in the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an in-depth look at how it works, &lt;a href=&quot;https://isl.co/2016/03/a-slack-based-internet-of-things-iot-tracking-system-for-your-dog-hello-paw/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;read more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-overview&quot;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the latest ISL experiment, PAW was comprised of a small internal team that brought the product to life in a few short weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I served as front-end developer for the public facing marketing page and also helped in the styling of the internal dashboard application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had the opportunity to explore animating SVGs through CSS (thanks to the illustrative work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/sarahsugarman&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Sarah Sugarman&lt;/a&gt;) and worked with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/krawchyk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Andrew Krawchyk&lt;/a&gt;, the project’s development lead, to implement some of the front-end application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/paw/paw-marketing-page-screenshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	    
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow end&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/paw/paw-dashboard-screenshots.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;animating-svgs&quot;&gt;Animating SVGs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I began development, I wanted to work on animating the various components of the marketing page’s hero illustration in order to create a playful and interesting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by exporting three parts of the scene for animation: a coffee mug, the computer screen, and, of course, Watson – our PAW mascot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After combing through the SVG code, I targeted specific shapes for animation and got them moving through the use of CSS animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p data-height=&quot;750&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;light&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;LGBbOv&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;alxmrtnz&quot; data-embed-version=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/alxmrtnz/pen/LGBbOv/&quot;&gt;Workspace Animation&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Martinez (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/alxmrtnz&quot;&gt;@alxmrtnz&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

		&lt;span class=&quot;img-caption&quot;&gt;Animating SVGs through CSS gave the landing page illustration a life of its own.&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explored animation loops through relatively simple CSS properties. Elements like the coffee’s steam were particularly interesting because of the need for offset timing to achieve an effect of easing in and out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsive-development&quot;&gt;Responsive Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to working on SVG animations, my other task at hand was to develop the public-facing marketing page and also to lend support for the internal application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/paw/paw-responsive-screenshots.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/paw/paw-homepage-screenshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PAW is currently available to ISL employees only. To learn more about PAW, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://isl.co/2016/03/a-slack-based-internet-of-things-iot-tracking-system-for-your-dog-hello-paw/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://paw.isl.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;visit the site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 14:46:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/work/paw.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/paw.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Family Online Safety Institute</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid--featured-image grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/featured-image-fosi.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fosi.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Family Online Safety Institute&lt;/a&gt; (FOSI) came to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isl.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;ISL&lt;/a&gt; to redesign and rebuild their website. Our mission was twofold — to combine fosi.org and aplaftormforgood.org (now Good Digital Parenting) under one umbrella, and to create a beautiful design and a user friendly experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The redesign process involved diving deep into Google Analytics, conducting user testing with key audiences, and unifying the two sites through detailed wireframing and design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working closely with our client, we successfully created a digital hub for online safety news, research, and events. With a focus on information architecture and design, the project aimed to reorganize content and present it in a digestible, mobile-friendly format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-the-audience&quot;&gt;Understanding the Audience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new fosi.org was a challenge due to its wide range of intended audiences. In addition to online safety information for families, the site needed to cater professionals seeking out industry conferences and events to policy makers who utilize FOSI’s many research articles in everyday work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;personas&quot;&gt;Personas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to better understand each type of user, we created a variety personas to serve as references throughout the design process. By working closely with the FOSI team, we could ensure that the personas accurately reflected the intended audiences. We used these personas as a reference for any debates or decisions throughout the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/persona-david.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	    
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half end&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/persona-mary.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-flows&quot;&gt;User Flows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fictional personas allowed us to create user flows that aided in the identification of discrete goals and actions for each type of user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-user-flow-david.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;site-structure&quot;&gt;Site Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After analyzing user flows and also interviewing stakeholders, we reorganized content into three main buckets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Family Resources (a.k.a. “Good Digital Parenting”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policy and Research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reorganization and consolidation of the site’s content makes it easier than ever for each audience to discover what they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-sitemap-pt1.png&quot; alt=&quot;FOSI.org Sitemap pt. 1&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-sitemap-pt2.png&quot; alt=&quot;FOSI.org Sitemap pt. 2&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prototyping&quot;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the functionality we wanted to include in the site, such as a sticky navigation and fixed filters, are often difficult to describe to clients using static wireframes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better communicate the small details that would improve the new FOSI experience, our team created a set of animated wireframes in addition to our standard wireframe set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/155266319?autoplay=1&amp;amp;loop=1&amp;amp;loop=1&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-wireframes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FOSI.org Wireframes&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;typography&quot;&gt;Typography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to be inviting to parents, yet authoritative and reliable to professionals, I chose typefaces that mixed organic sans-serif headings with more traditional serifed text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-type-example.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aaux-next&quot;&gt;Aaux Next&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaux Next is an approachabe sans-serif that was chosen for headings due to its mix of solid structure and rounded, more quirky, characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;minion-pro&quot;&gt;Minion Pro&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minion Pro exhibits functional qualities that makes text highly readable. I chose it to give formality and legibility to the site’s main content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;colors&quot;&gt;Colors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With content being broken up into several main sections, I defined colors that would be related to each type of content (green for Good Digital Parenting, red for Policy &amp;amp; Research, etc). By tying specific colors to content, we were able to visually separate internal platforms each internal platform and give the user clear context to their location on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt grid-mb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full no-shadow&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-colors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fin-tip&quot;&gt;	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
	A Flexible, Responsive Publishing Platform
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, the new FOSI.org is a multi-faceted publishing platform. From online-safety print outs to the latest research on internet privacy, FOSI works to publish educational content that helps families (and the industry at large) learn and grow in the new digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By creating flexible layouts, a new design system, and an integration with Wagtail, a Django-based CMS, we were able to provide FOSI with a rethought and redesigned responsive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid grid-mt &quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--full&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-homepage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FOSI.org Homepage&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-gdp-tablet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FOSI.org Good Digital Parenting Page screenshot (tablet)&quot; /&gt;
	    
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half no-shadow end&quot;&gt;
	    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/work/fosi/fosi-events-phone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FOSI.org Events Page screenshot (mobile)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 14:46:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/work/fosi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/fosi.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Five of My Favorite Sketch Plugins</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;You know what’s awesome about Sketch? Quite a lot of things. One of my favorites? Plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I switched over from Photoshop to Sketch as my primary web design tool, I had used Photoshop plugins. However, I often found myself frustrated with how to find, download, install, and configure them. With Sketch, it’s a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sketch-toolbox&quot;&gt;Sketch Toolbox&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/11-28-15/sketch-toolbox.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sketch Toolbox Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
Before we dive into my favorite plugins, if you use Sketch and you haven’t installed &lt;a href=&quot;http://sketchtoolbox.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Sketch Toolbox&lt;/a&gt; yet, prepare to be excited. Sketch Toolbox is an application created by members of the Sketch community that lets you easily manage your plugins. Definitely check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, some of my favorite plugins:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsgithubcomutomsketch-measure-targetblank-classlink--headingsketch-measurea&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/utom/sketch-measure&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--heading&quot;&gt;Sketch Measure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/utom/sketch-measure&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/11-28-15/sketch-measure-example.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Sketch Measure Animated Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sketch Measure is an invaluable tool for annotating your design comps. The plugin helps you create markings to show heights, widths, paddings, and margins of elements. It’s great for sharing designs with developers or fellow designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsgithubcomandrewfiorillosketch-palettes-targetblank-classlink--headingsketch-palettesa&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andrewfiorillo/sketch-palettes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--heading&quot;&gt;Sketch Palettes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andrewfiorillo/sketch-palettes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/11-28-15/sketch-palettes-screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sketch Measure Animated Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve used Photoshop, then you’re familiar with how you can save out and load sets of color swatches. This kind of color management is especially useful if you’re working on a project with a lot of other designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Sketch doesn’t come with the same functionality. Each new file requires you to re-add colors one-by-one. Setting up colors in file after file can get old pretty fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the Sketch Palettes plugin lets you export and later load sets of colors into your new Sketch files. Save, load, and presto! Quick color palettes in Sketch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsgithubcomddwhtsketch-dynamic-button-targetblank-classlink--headingdynamic-buttonsa&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ddwht/sketch-dynamic-button&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--heading&quot;&gt;Dynamic Buttons&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ddwht/sketch-dynamic-button&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/11-28-15/dynamic-buttons-screenshot.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Dynamic Buttons Animated Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever created a button with the perfect size but then had to change the text and readjust its padding? Fret no more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamic Buttons allows you to specify the padding of your button and then, whenever you change the text within, you can use a simple keyboard shortcut dynamically readjust its padding. Pixel perfect button padding made simple. Oh, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@poohbers/dynamic-button-sketch-plugin-946638e73398#.t29zevs6g&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here’s a quick how-to!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsgithubcomshahruzsend-to-slack-targetblank-classlink--headingsend-to-slacka&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shahruz/Send-to-Slack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--heading&quot;&gt;Send to Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shahruz/Send-to-Slack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/11-28-15/send-to-slack-example.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Send to Slack Animated Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;https://isl.co&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ISL&lt;/a&gt;, we constantly use Slack to message each other about anything and everything. Slack has also become a fast way to share and discuss designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Send to Slack plugin, you can quickly send an art board in Sketch to anyone on your Slack team. Instead of having to export and upload art boards, the plugin lets you select a user or channel to export and upload to all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsgithubcomgetflourishsketch-color-contrast-analyser-targetblank-classlink--headingcolor-contrast-analyser-for-sketcha&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/getflourish/Sketch-Color-Contrast-Analyser&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--heading&quot;&gt;Color Contrast Analyser for Sketch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/getflourish/Sketch-Color-Contrast-Analyser&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/11-28-15/sketch-color-analyser-screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sketch Measure Animated Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/11/11/conference-recap-fowd-sf.html#web-accessibility-is-more-than-accessible-code&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Jennison Asuncion’s talk&lt;/a&gt;  at the FOWD conference, accessible design has been on my mind. The Color Contrast Analyzer plugin lets you find out if the colors in your design have a high enough contrast for users with low vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plugin adheres to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;W3’s accessibility guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and instantly shows you what rating your work would receive (A, AA, AAA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-theres-more&quot;&gt;And there’s more…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of Sketch plugins is growing every day thanks to a thriving Sketch community. Do you have any favorite plugins? Let me know below!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 14:46:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/thoughts/five-of-my-favorite-sketch-plugins.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thoughts/five-of-my-favorite-sketch-plugins.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To the Future (of Web Design)&lt;br&gt;A Conference Recap</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about being a part of a design team at an agency like ISL is getting the opportunity to grow both creatively and professionally. Our company makes a huge effort to support our team’s growth and encourages employees to attend industry conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I attended the Future of Web Design (FOWD) conference in San Francisco. The conference was a 3-day event for designers, front-end developers, and other creatives working to make the web a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the biggest lessons I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-source-design-is-a-pretty-awesome-thing&quot;&gt;Open Source Design is a (Pretty Awesome) Thing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most inspiring talk came from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/garthdb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Garth Braithwaite&lt;/a&gt;, a product designer and front-end developer on PhoneGap at Adobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garth discussed the benefits of open source design and detailed some of his work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nightscout.info/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;NightScout&lt;/a&gt;, an app developed by parents of children with Type 1 Diabetes to remotely help track blood sugar levels (and save lives). By connecting data from a monitoring device, parents can send live updates to their phones and smartwatches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His advice for getting into open source?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s designing a logo, contributing code, or just adding a new perspective to the conversation, he recommends finding something you’re passionate about. There are also some &lt;a href=&quot;http://opendesign.foundation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/opensourcedesign&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;places&lt;/a&gt; you can go to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;side-projects-are-stupid-and-theyre-supposed-to-be&quot;&gt;Side Projects are Stupid… and They’re Supposed to Be&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been looking forward to meeting &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/schneidertobias&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Tobias van Schneider&lt;/a&gt; (and his luscious beard) for some time. Tobias is a German-born designer that recently led the Spotify brand refresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He talked about keeping side projects fun and stupid. This way, you can keep from overthinking the work. From &lt;a href=&quot;http://authenticweather.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Authentic Weather&lt;/a&gt; to his own &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beardbrand.com/products/black-marble-beard-oil&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;line of beard oil&lt;/a&gt;, Tobias has followed through on some downright silly ideas. Some guiding principles for successful side projects? Let yourself be stupid, ignore everybody (they all have their own ideas and opinions of how things should be), trust your gut, and stay busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-accessibility-is-more-than-accessible-code&quot;&gt;Web Accessibility is More than Accessible Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As practitioners of web design and development, it’s our job to make our websites usable, visually pleasing, and accessible – and that doesn’t mean just developers/engineers implementing accessible code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Jennison&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;Jennison Asuncion&lt;/a&gt;, Co-Director of the Adaptech Research Network, spoke about how producing accessible content means designing and developing user experiences that everyone, including people with disabilities, can independently consume and interact with. From touching on resources for &lt;a href=&quot;http://jxnblk.com/colorable/demos/text/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;sufficient color contrast&lt;/a&gt; to walking us through the experience of using a screenreader on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.united.com/ual/en/us/?root=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;United.com&lt;/a&gt;, Jennison got me thinking about how web professionals can (and should) improve accessibility across their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a first web conference experience, FOWD was a blast and extremely inspiring. If you’re a web professional or have just been thinking about putting yourself out there and learning how we creatives can help impact the world around us, I’d highly recommend attending a conference like FOWD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m already planning my next steps of finding and contributing to an open source project, working to make my sites more accessible, and might even be thinking about my own beard oil – well, we’ll see about that last one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 14:46:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/thoughts/conference-recap-fowd-sf.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thoughts/conference-recap-fowd-sf.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where We Belong</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Hello there, how you doin’?
I’ve got all these thoughts just floating through my brain…” - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pISPVfRQiOo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;link--text-in-p&quot;&gt;MCS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had something back in high school we referred to as the JEP (Junior English Project). Taught by the wonderful, yet eccentric, Darrin Broadway, the junior english struck fear into the hearts of many. The project consisted of a string of readings, assignments, and essays throughout the school year that culminated in each student developing a final project – whether that project be a short story, poem, interpretive dance, documentary, film, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing exercises, the constant pressure, the unrelenting deadlines forced out some of our most creative work of our young lives. The insurmountable idea of having to pump out thousands and thousands of words for a 10-page paper on the themes of Fahrenheit 451 dwindled over time and instead turned into a fuel that fed our minds and our fingers as we wrote (or typed) late into the weeknights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it was some of my best writing. Crafting outlines for essays became second nature and filling them in with carefully considered dabs of light hearted banter with logically executed conclusions became an art at which (at least thought) I thrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say that I was really that great of a writer. For all intents and purposes, I was a 17 year old kid writing a standard 5 paragraph essay on a book we had been assigned to read. But at times, through the many assignments and long nights, I felt that words were truly a medium of unbounded expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I may be setting myself and this catalogue of thoughts up for failure with that prologue, however, I’m hoping that the result will be quite the opposite. My goal? Pen my thoughts on design, code, happiness, and life. Thanks for tuning in.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 15:46:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/thoughts/hello-there.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thoughts/hello-there.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
